<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JBake</title>
    <link>https://blog.schedulemyteachers.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.schedulemyteachers.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>JBake Bootstrap Template</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 22:59:40 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 22:59:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Why use Schedule My Teachers?</title>
      <link>https://blog.schedulemyteachers.com/blog/2018/04/why-schedule-my-teachers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 1 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2018/04/why-schedule-my-teachers.html</guid>
      	<description>
	&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;to_save_time&quot;&gt;To Save Time&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Using Schedule My Teachers saves administrators an average of 9 hours! That’s the power of our school schedule maker. You’ve got better things to do than spend a day and a half creating your school’s class schedule, so let us help you get back to the more important things.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;to_find_the_best_schedule_possible&quot;&gt;To Find the Best Schedule Possible&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;When you make your school schedule by hand, it’s tempting to stop searching for solutions once you’ve found a schedule that works. But by settling for the suboptimal, you could be affecting student learning and teacher satisfaction. Schedule My Teachers helps you find the best schedule possible given your needs and wants.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;because_it_s_easy_to_use&quot;&gt;Because it’s Easy to Use&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Our school schedule maker is intuitive and designed with the user in mind. The scheduler consists of six easy steps, each with helpful descriptions and hints right on the page. We also put a tutorial tab in the scheduler itself. This means that our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChZSVxOje6swSYQn7d1dqWg/videos&quot;&gt;step-by-step tutorial videos&lt;/a&gt; are just a click away if you need them. Each one clearly demonstrates exactly how to complete each step.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Simultaneously make the best school schedule with ease and save time today!&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
	</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ask Yourself These Five Questions Before Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://blog.schedulemyteachers.com/blog/2018/03/five-questions-before-scheduling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 1 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">blog/2018/03/five-questions-before-scheduling.html</guid>
      	<description>
	&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;what_are_my_school_s_priorities&quot;&gt;What are my school’s priorities?&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;If you want to know what a school values, look at how it orders its day. Subjects considered essential rightly receive more class time. So before you make your school’s schedule, know what is important to your school. Do the humanities take precedence over STEM or vice versa? Do you see your flex period, which allows students to receive one-to-one attention, as very important for student success? Answering these types of questions first will make your school scheduling a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;which_subject_should_be_first&quot;&gt;Which subject should be first?&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Students are more alert and ready to learn early in the school day. Take advantage of this by putting a particularly difficult or important subject first. By using our school schedule maker, you can easily do this by assigning a particular class to a particular period.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;which_subjects_should_be_before_and_after_lunch&quot;&gt;Which subjects should be before and after lunch?&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Lunch gives students (and teachers) a much needed break and energy boost. However, the class immediately prior can be a struggle. Think twice about putting a difficult class in its slot. Lots of schools find it beneficial to have a lighter subject taught at this time. Likewise, the class immediately after lunch deserves some thought as well. The extra energy should be used well, but gym class might not be the best option given their full stomachs. Again, whatever you decide is easily taken care of with our school scheduling software.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;which_subjects_should_be_back_to_back&quot;&gt;Which subjects should be back-to-back?&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes the sequence of classes relative to one another is just as important as their order in the day. Think through what classes would pair well together. Math and then history? Spanish before English? Music after gym? Or maybe back-to-back science classes would allow for science labs. Either way, sequencing your subjects appropriately is an effective way to promote learning.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; 
 &lt;h3 id=&quot;which_teachers_would_benefit_by_having_prep_periods_together&quot;&gt;Which teachers would benefit by having prep periods together?&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;The school schedule not only dictates when students have which classes when, it also determines when teachers have prep periods. Teachers who teach the same grade level would greatly benefit from having a common prep period during the week since it allows them to collaborate and plan together without having to setup a separate meeting time. If you utilize professional learning communities (PLCs), providing a common prep for each PLC allows its members to meet during the school day instead of before or after school. This is a great convenience for your teachers and demonstrates that you value their work. While using our school scheduler, assigning the same ‘Unavailable Period’ to each teacher who needs a common prep period will ensure that they are not scheduled to teach during that time and will be free to meet.&lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;
	</description>
    </item>

  </channel> 
</rss>
